# **Lisa Pritchard**

Wynnewood, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Lisa-Pritchard/f2cb6174dcf59ef1

Experienced Management Professional with strong leadership skills. Ability to initiate projects and problem solve creatively while improving operations and customer service across all industries. Have a reputation to be driven, passionate about customer service excellence, sales, detailed orientated, while executing processes and accomplishing goals. Exceptional interpersonal, communication as well as verbal and written skills.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Sales Associate, Fashion Jewelry and Watches

Nordstrom - King of Prussia, PA - 2014 to Present

Maintain a fashionable and professional image as a customer service role model.

- Consistently seek new fashion and product knowledge to act as an expert for the customer
- Search for innovative ways to increase business through use of Personal Book, store traffic, customer referrals, website requests and personal networking
- Provide expertise and honest confident feedback regarding merchandise style and fit.
- Use directive selling skills through cross, team and on-line selling to maximize the customer's wardrobe needs.
- Build lasting relationships by contacting customers to follow up on purchases, suggest new merchandise and invite them to upcoming store events.
- Set and achieve personal daily, monthly, yearly and special event goals.

#### **Program Manager**

Penn Medicine and The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA - July 2012 to February 2014

07/2012 - 02 /2014

Philadelphia Adult Congenital Heart Center, Department of Cardio Vascular Medicine Program Manager

- \* Developed and executed strategic plans accomplishing an increase of 10% patient referrals and transition of care by introducing the program to primary care physicians and area cardiologists.
- \* Improved the overall operational systems putting processes into place allowing team members and patient care to become seamless.
- \* Assist in the management and the relationship between Philadelphia Adult Congenital Heart Center and stakeholders to promote effective multidisciplinary care.
- \* Cultivate a culture of high performance and customer service by communicating the overall patient experience and expectations through building patient relationships, and marketing materials.
- \* Reduced no show visits, by 5 % standardizing confirming appointments and verification of insurance pre certification.
- \* Collaborated with outreach programs, events and websites with Penn and CHOP marketing teams to build awareness of the program.
- \* Managed administrative staff and operations to ensure a smooth workflow.

## **Associate Director of Access and Clinical Operations**

Penn Medicine - January 2001 to June 2012

Managed operations for the main ophthalmology site as well as two smaller locations.

- \* Assisted the Director of Operations in short and long term goals to ensure financial and operational success.
- \* Led the project implementation of a major access initiative related to conversion of clinical scheduling from a 23 plus year mature environment to a Windows based integrated system that impacts daily operations and revenue generation.
- \* Managed the team of thirty plus physician administrative assistants, front desk associates, surgical schedulers and medical record associates for the department.
- \* Collaborated with physicians and administration to achieve positive patient outcomes with respect to problem solving to improve overall patient satisfaction experience.
- \* Increased overall patient satisfaction 20% by empowering associates to anticipate patients' needs and expectations.
- \* Expanding patient appointment availability by collaborating with physicians in adjusting daily schedules to the needs of the patients.
- \* Assisted with the initial project implementation of converting paper medical records to electronic medical records September 2010. This led to greater efficiency in documentation and billing and a 20% reduction needed in medical records personnel.
- \* Continually educated staff on Electronic Medical Records so that they may be efficient and fluent in the process.
- \* Conducted interviews, recruiting and selecting employees for front desk, administrative assistants and medical record positions.
- \* Facilitated the capture of physician and technical charges for the department. Educated front desk staff and Administrative assistants.
- \* Responsible for developing, implementing and quality assurance of scheduling protocols, policies, procedures, and processes for daily schedule changes for each provider.
- \* Partnered with the call center team to educate and strengthen their knowledge of each sub-specialty in ophthalmology.
- \* In conjunction with Director of Health Information Management organized the development, implementation, and maintenance of record handling protocols, policies, and procedures to ensure efficient processing of information.

## Manager of Refractive Services

Penn Medicine - July 1999 to January 2008

Initiated the execution and operation of the Vision Surgery and Laser Center at Penn Eye Care,

October 1999. \* Designed and implemented a sales process in which the client is provided with an excellent service experience throughout the refractive surgery process. Reached a goal of 90% refractive surgery patient conversion. Built relationships with patients by answering all of their questions and anticipating their needs so that our practice grew by positive word of mouth experience.

- \* Managed the financial and revenue operations of refractive surgery by meeting target numbers of 30 surgeries per month and a goal of 95% of 20/40 vision or better.
- \* Collaborated with marketing to establish brand name, educational materials and trends in the refractive surgery market.

# **Business Manager**

Eye Physicians Management Corporation - January 1999 to July 1999

Managed the financial operations of Eye Physicians Management

- \* Directed and operated a buying group for ophthalmic products such as frames, lenses, and contact lenses for a group of physicians participating in the network.
- \* Generated monthly invoices and collected account receivables.
- \* Performed optical consulting through out the physician network.

## General Manager, Retail Manager Assistant Retail Manager

LensCrafters, Luxottica Group - December 1987 to January 1999

Responsible for the operations and sales of two million dollar store and the production of quality eyewear, while maintaining high productivity level, achieving budgetary goals.

- \* Assisted in opening of four stores in the Philadelphia area by hiring, training, setting up inventory and operations.
- \* Analyzed productivity, encounters per hour, and quality of eye wear. Managed and forecasted sales, inventory, and staffing.
- \* Planned and organized monthly store budgets.
- \* Regional lead trainer for a computer scheduling system that would schedule associates by trends of sales and productivity rather than when employees were available. This led to a 20% increase of customer satisfaction.
- \* Positive profit and loss statements were achieved for the store on a monthly basis allowing bonus metric goals to be reached on a semiannual basis.
- \* Set goals and strategic plans with team members looking at overall outcomes and trends.
- \* Developed creative displays and merchandising products for sales floor.
- \* Foster business-to-business relationship with local ophthalmologists to build awareness of our products and to increase sales.

## **EDUCATION**

# Management

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA

# **B** S in Design and Merchandising

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### COMPUTER SKILLS:

Microsoft Word, Excel, Power Point & Outlook, POS Systems, IDX, EPIC EMR, and APM.